Mss.Rec.30 Mss.Rec.30
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Mrs. Chester Johnson's Song to teqwedi-yAtx'i, yAnyedi-yAtx'i, and cAnkuqedi-yAtx'i, 1954-04-29; 05-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:45; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Chester, Mrs.
    "[Song] was composed in 1942 when her first husband died, and she had to go to Juneau for an operation. The secord verse is addresed to Maggy Harry who was also undergoing an operation." Recording ends with identification song and previously recorded song. See Related Recording.
  - Song of Slave, gucdutin, (incorrect version), 1954-04-07; 05-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:33; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Minnie
    Indian slaves--Alaska; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Song of the Slave, gucdutin, 1954-04-07; 05-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:53; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Minnie
    "Minnie introduces the song in Tlingit. It was composed by her mother's father's slave, gocdutin. He gave his master's sib, the teqwedi, the song and the face-paint pattern he used when he escaped. Cf. Swanton Song 68." Recording ends with identification song and previously recorded song. See Related Recording.
  - Blind Dave Dick's Song, rebuking his brother's wife, to teqwedi-yAtx'i, 1954-04-29; 05-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:10; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Chester, Mrs.; Johnson, Minnie
    A song addressed to Mrs. Jack Peterson, accusing her of backsliding as a Christian, because she had quarreled with Blind Dave, her brother-in-law. Recording concludes with an explanation of the song in English by Minnie Johnson.
  - Maggy Harry's Father's Song, to teqwedi-yAtx'i, 1954-05-27; 05-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:20; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Harry, Maggy
    "Maggy Harry introduces her father's song. It was composed in 1892 to her mother. 'He was dying when he sang that song.'" Recording ends with identification of song by Frederica de Laguna.
  - Thunder Blanket Song, cInkuqedi, 1954-06-10; 05-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:12; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Chester, Mrs.; White, Jenny
    "Mrs. C. Johnson introduces the song in Tlingit. It was composed before her mother was born.... Only one stanza is sung. Mrs. C.J. didn't want to record the second." Song identified by Frederica de Laguna at the end of the subsequently recorded song. See Related Recording.
  - Thunder Blanket Song, 1954-06-10; 05-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:21; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Chester, Mrs.
    Recording ends with identification of this song and the song recorded prior to it by Frederica de Laguna. For other song, see Related Recording.
  - Shaman's Song, 1954-06-10; 05-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:44; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Chester, Mrs.
    "Mrs. Chester Johnson introduces the song in Tlingit. It belonged to her father's mother's father, qalaXetl or ltuneX'. His spirit was tlIngit-ani-Adi qu yek or Smallpox Spirit, probably referring to the epidemic of 1838." Recording ends with identification of song by Frederica de Laguna.
    Shamanism--Alaska; Smallpox--Alaska; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit Indians--Religion; Tsimshian language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Another Shaman's Song, 1954-06-10; 05-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:37; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Chester, Mrs.
    Mrs. Chester Johnson introduces the song in Tlingit. One of four songs belonging to her father's mother's father; also given by the Smallpox Spirits. The words are in Tsimshian. Recording ends with identification of this song and the song recorded prior to it by Frederica de Laguna. For other song, see Related Recording.
  - Song to FdeLaguna, 1954-06-10; 05-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:20; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Chester, Mrs.
    "Mrs. Chester Johnson sings 1 stanza, just composed by herself, to an old tune, addressed to FdeL; to tcicqedi-yAtx'i." Recording ends with identification of song by Frederica de Laguna.
  - Shaman's Song, 1954-05-10; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:10; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jack, Jenny
    "Jenny Jack sings shaman's song belonging to t'ek'-ic. The spirit is gAgan-yAtx'i, Sun's Children. The words are Tsimshian."
  - Jenny Jack's Own song, to kagwantan-yAtx'i, 1954-05-10; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:29; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jack, Jenny
    "This song was composed in 1939 when George Bremner, her husband's nephew, was drowned in Ankaw."
  - B.A. Jack's Song, 1954-05-10; 06-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:07; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jack, Jenny; Williams, Sarah
    A song composed by B A Jack when he was lonesome on a hunting trip near Mt. St. Elias. He gave her the song when he died. He died about 1948. The song was composed about 1909. The song is explained by Sarah Williams in Tlingit.
  - Three Tlingit Songs, 1954-05-10; 06-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:42; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Williams, Sarah
    "(a) Song composed by Sarah Williams about a white soldier who was stationed in Yakutat during the war, and believed killed in the Aleutians. (b and c) Two songs in English, composed by school girls in Sitka."
    Soldiers--Alaska; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Raven & Herrings and Raven & Snipes, 1954-05-10; 06-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:38; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jack, Jenny; Williams, Sarah
    "These two short songs were attempted 3 times. The third version is correct."
  - Killerwhale Drum Song, 1954-05-12; 06-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:01; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Milton, Nick
    "Nick Milton sings. He said that they had made a mistake in the words of the second stanza when the song was sung 4/25/54. There should be two or three different voices for the song." Recording concludes with identification of the song by Frederica de Laguna. For previously recorded version of song, see Related Recording.
    Tepehuan Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Teqwedi Walking Song, 1954-05-12; 06-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:22; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Milton, Nick
    "[Song] has Tsimshian words, and was perhaps one obtained about 1900 from Tsimshian sea-otter hunters at Yakutat, because they were sorry they nearly started a fight with the Yakutat Tlingit over a disputed sea-otter. It is used when the teqwedi guests at a potlatch enter and leave the house to which they have been invited." Recording concludes with identification of the song by Frederica de Laguna.
    Potlatch; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit Indians--History; Tsimshian Indians--History; Tsimshian language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Teqwedi Dancing Song, 1954-05-12; 06-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:31; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Milton, Nick
    "[Song] lacks words." Recording concludes with identification of the song by Frederica de Laguna.
    Tlingit dance; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Rites and ceremonies; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - First Stanza of Teqwedi Mourning Song, for men lost getting green stone near Sitka, [cf. Swanton, 1909, p. 46], 1954-05-12; 06-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:09; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Milton, Nick
    Recording concludes with identification of the song by Frederica de Laguna.
  - Shaman's Song, 1954-05-12; 06-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:39; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Milton, Nick
    "Nick Milton speaks in Tlingit about the song. The spirits were the children of the Sun and of a teqwedi woman whose relatives had all been killed in a war. These spirits came from SE Alaska but passed over all the other sibs. They came first to Xatgawet, a rich teqwedi shaman who lived on Knight Island, and were later inherited by t'ek'-ic who died in the 1880's." Recording concludes with identification of the song by Frederica de Laguna.
  - Humorous Peace Dance Song; Raven Washes Himself, 1954-05-16; 06-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:33; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Chester, Mrs.
    Raven (Legendary character); Tlingit dance; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Rites and ceremonies; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Song for the Frog Screen, 1954-05-17; 06-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:34; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Dick, Frank, Mrs.
    "Mrs. Frank Dick begins to explain the story of how the tl'uknaxAdi found the Frog at Alsek. 'cuxwanAx de xixtc'....'" For previously recorded version of song, and translation of song and related story, see Related Recording.
    Frogs--Folklore; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Raven Cries for Daylight, 1954-05-17; 06-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:21; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Dick, Frank, Mrs.
  - Half of wuckika's Song of Mourning, 1954-05-17; 06-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:52; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Dick, Frank, Mrs.; Dick, Frank
    "This song was composed by the woman whose relatives were drowned in Lituya Bay, over a century ago."
  - Athabaskan Song for Coming Under the Ice on the Alsek, 1954-05-17; 06-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:49; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Dick, Frank, Mrs.; Dick, Frank
    A song supposed to be several hundred years old that is sung when people have successfully passed down the Alsek River under the glaciers. The words of the song in "Athabaskan," mostly like Southern Tutchone.
    Alsek River; Athapascan Indians--Alaska--Music; Southern Tutchone language; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Song for Coming Under the Ice, 1954-05-17; 06-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:21; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Dick, Frank
  - Frank Italio's Song for the First Mrs. Frank Dick; to cAnkuqedi-yAtx'i and kagwantan-yAtx'i, 1954-05-17; 06-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:11; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Dick, Frank, Mrs.
  - Dry Bay George's Song, to gIneX-qwan-yAtx'i, 1954-05-17; 06-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:47; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Dick, Frank, Mrs.
    "This was composed by tlIngit-ani-kina, the brother of Dry Bay Chief George." Recording cuts off before completion of program.
  - Song for Murrelet Staff, wuckiten sib, 1954-06-10; 07-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:32; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Chester, Mrs.
    "Mrs. Chester Johnson introduces the song in Tlingit. It is a sad song belonging to the sib of her father's father's father's father, and is probably very old." Recording concludes with identification of the song by Frederica de Laguna.
  - Dry Bay Chief George's Song to his young girl friend, 1954-06-10; 07-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:37; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Chester, Mrs.; White, Jenny
  - Marching Song (kwack'qwan), 1954-05-27; 07-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Harry, Maggy; Jack, Jenny
    "Maggy Harry introduces the song in Tlingit. It is one supposedly used as a marching song by the ancestors of the kwack'qwan on their migration from the Copper River; now used by the kwack'qwan when marching to a house to which they have been invited as guests at a potlatch."
    Indians of North America--Migrations; Migration, Internal--Alaska; Potlatch--Alaska; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Resting Song (kwack'qwan), 1954-05-27; 07-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:15; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Harry, Maggy; Jack, Jenny
    The words of the song are identified by collector as being "in Copper River Language." This most likely designates Eyak.
    Eyak language; Indians of North America--Migrations; Migration, Internal--Alaska; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Mourning Song (kwack'qwan), 1954-05-27; 07-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:15; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Harry, Maggy; Jack, Jenny
    "Maggy Harry introduces the song in Tlingit. It was composed on the migration from Copper River, by a man who shot his brother by mistake, and is now sung at potlatches 'when we lost our parents.'" The words of the song are identified by collector as being "in Copper River Language." This most likely designates Eyak.
  - Jimmy Jackson's Love Song, 1904, 1954-05-27; 07-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:19; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Harry, Maggy; Jack, Jenny
    "Maggy Harry introduces the song in Tlingit. It was composed in 1904, by her uncle, Jimmy Jackson, when his wife, Susie Davis, left him, and his sister-in-law offered to be his girl friend.... This is not addressed to any sib -yAtx'i. It is supposed to sound like the sawmill in which Jimmy Jackson was working at the time. However, it is supposed to be of Haida type, like the conventional songs addressed to sib-yAtx'i."
    Haida Indians--Music; Love songs; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Haida Love Song, 1954-05-27; 07-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:05; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Harry, Maggy; Jack, Jenny
    "Maggy Harry explains in Tlingit that the song was purchased in Kasaan, from a Haida man named q'ackwe, by B.A. Jack, and Maggy's husband, tcAna-ic, in 1900. 'It's pretty fast.'"
  - kwack'qwan "National Song", 1954-05-27; 07-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:10; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Harry, Maggy
    Shamanism--Alaska; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit Indians--Religion; Tlingit language; Tsimshian language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Song composed by Jimmy Jackson for sanAX-tla; to kagwantan-yAtx'i, 1954-05-27; 07-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:57; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jack, Jenny
    "Jenny Jack introduces the song in Tlingit, beginning 'aX cAtX...' The song was composed by Jimmy Jackson to comfort Jenny's cousin, sanAX-tla, when she was beaten up by her husband for getting into trouble with Tom John's older brother, kUXt'itc. Maggy says: 'We gonna help her.'"
    Family violence--Alaska; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - kwack'qwan Mourning Song for those Drowned, 1954-05-27; 07-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:45; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Harry, Maggy; Jack, Jenny
    "Maggy introduces the song in Tlingit. Then- 'It's a pretty sad song, this one. I always cry when I sing it, but I'm gonna try to brave enough to sing it.' [Mourning song for those who drown. It is addressed to the dead son. Composed in Chilkat on Bering River by kagwask' about 1860 ? when his brother was lost on a snowslide."
    Drowning victims; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Aleut Sun Dance Song, 1954-05-27; 07-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:51; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Harry, Maggy; Jack, Jenny
    "Maggy introduces the song in Tlingit...'You tell them fine looking girls gonna sing this song.' Laughs. [It is a dance song, in which the dancers pretend to push 'them' around with guns. It was an Aleut - i.e. Prince William Sound Eskimo song - captured by cada, Maggy's great-grandfather in a war with the 'Aleut' near Cordova."
    Aleuts--Music; Tlingit dance; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Funny Song about Raven Breaking Box of Daylight, 1954-05-31; 07-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:44; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Minnie
    "This is sung as a funny song at the end of a peace ceremony. Minnie ends with a waa! which has to be called out if the peace-hostage makes a mistake or says anything that might provoke bad feelings."
    Raven (Legendary character); Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Rites and ceremonies; Tlingit language; Yakutat (Alaska)
  - Funny Song about Raven loosing his nose, 1954-05-31; 07-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:13; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Minnie
  - Sarani (Crow) Song, 1954-07-12; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:24; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine; Stanfield, Fanny
    "It is a potlatch dancing song from Up-the-Line, Copper Center or Chistochina. The words apparently mean: 'When he's flying around, the Crow says he's going to see you some day.'" Recording identified by Frederica de Laguna at end of subsequently recorded song. See Related Recording.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chitina (Alaska); Crows; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska
  - Chalali Whisky Song, 1954-07-12; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine; Stanfield, Fanny
    A dancing song, to which men and women dance in a circle. May come from Copper Center. Words mean, 'Put the whisky in the cup.' Recording identified by Frederica de Laguna at end of subsequently recorded song. See Related Recording.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chitina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Whiskey
  - Potlatch Song, 1954-07-12; 08-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:22; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine; Stanfield, Fanny
    "This song is said to be sung from Chitina to Cordova. The words sound like Athabaskan pronunciation of Tlingit." Recording identified by Frederica de Laguna at end of subsequently recorded song. See Related Recording.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chitina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska
  - Fanny's Mother's Song, 1954-07-12; 08-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:29; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine; Stanfield, Fanny
    "This song was not composed by her mother, but was one her mother used to sing. It was learned from the Eyak?" Recording concludes with identification of this song and the three preceding ones by Frederica de Laguna. See Related Recording.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Chitina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language
  - A Tlingit Song, 1954-07-13; 08-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:52; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Goodlataw, Joe; McClellan, Catharine
    A song by the singer's father, a Tlingit, of the Eagle gIts'i'Iltcha sib. This was a happy song used at potlatches, when the champion dancers and singers were in the center, and the rest danced in a circle around them. Also formerly sung by the singer's elder brothers, Chief Nikolai and Chief Hangita, and Escaldita. Recording identified by Frederica de Laguna at end of subsequently recorded song. See Related Recording.
    Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chitina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska; Tlingit dance; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music
  - Another Tlingit Song, 1954-07-13; 08-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:34; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Goodlataw, Joe; McClellan, Catharine
    Recording identified by Frederica de Laguna at end of subsequently recorded song. See Related Recording.
    Chitina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language
  - Tlingit Worry Song, 1954-07-13; 08-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:37; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Goodlataw, Joe; Goodlataw, Martha; McClellan, Catharine
    "It came from SE Alaska, and was sung at potlatch for Joe's grandfather who drowned in the Copper River near Miles and Childs Glaciers. His grandmother used to sing it. It was also sung by his brother at the potlatch for the latter's wife who died in childbirth." Recording identified by Frederica de Laguna at end of subsequently recorded song. See Related Recording.
    Chitina (Alaska); Drowning victims; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language
  - Tenas Waski Drinking Song, Chinook Jargon, 1954-07-13; 08-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:37; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Goodlataw, Joe; Goodlataw, Martha; McClellan, Catharine
    "This song is believed to be Tlingit. Joe's uncle, Nikolai, used to drink and sing this song. He would pour liquor into the mouths of dancers as they danced passed him." Recording concludes with identification of this song and the three preceding ones by Frederica de Laguna. See Related Recording.
    Chinook jargon; Chitina (Alaska); Drinking songs--Alaska; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music
  - Up the Line Drinking Song (Tcecali), 1954-07-14; 08-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:32; Carlsen, Lottie; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Goodlataw, Martha; McClellan, Catharine
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chitina (Alaska); Drinking songs--Alaska; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Up-The-Line Dance Song, 1954-07-14; 08-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:25; Carlsen, Lottie; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Goodlataw, Martha; McClellan, Catharine
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chitina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Up-the-Line Dance Song, 1954-07-14; 08-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:41; Carlsen, Lottie; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Goodlataw, Martha; McClellan, Catharine
    Ahtena dance; Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chitina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Gospel Hymn "Yesterday, Today, Forever", 1954-07-14; 08-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:34; Carlsen, Lottie; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Goodlataw, Martha; McClellan, Catharine
    Recording concludes with identification of this song and the three preceding ones by Frederica de Laguna. See Related Recording.
    Chitina (Alaska); Hymns; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1954-08-05; 08-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:03; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Recorded at Tazlina Song Fest. Information identifying the song is missing from the collector's accompanying documentation. Available information gathered from recording itself.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tazlina (Alaska)
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1954-08-05; 08-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:02; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tanacross language; Tazlina (Alaska)
  - Tetlin Song, 1954-08-05; 08-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:14; Billum, Douglas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tazlina (Alaska); Upper Tanana language
  - Tanana River Dancing Song, 1954-08-05; 08-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:00; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tanacross language; Tazlina (Alaska)
  - Tanana River Song, 1954-08-05; 08-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:25; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1954-08-05; 08-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:38; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1954-08-05; 08-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:40; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - Sarani Song, 1954-08-05; 08-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:53; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Raven (Legendary character); Tazlina (Alaska)
  - Song about a lady who lost a baby, 1954-08-05; 08-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:19; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta